elcamino.edu 2019-05-02

# Privacy Policy

El Camino Community College District is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the El Camino Community College District website and governs data collection and usage. By using the El Camino Community College District website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

**Collection of your Personal Information**

El Camino Community College District collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. El Camino Community College District also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by El Camino Community College District. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by El Camino Community College District for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the El Camino Community College District website.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through El Camino Community College District's public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. 

El Camino Community College District encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from El Camino Community College District so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. El Camino Community College District is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the El Camino Community College District and El Camino Community College District family of websites.

**Use of your Personal Information**

El Camino Community College District collects and uses your personal information to operate the El Camino Community College District website and deliver the services you have requested. El Camino Community College District also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from El Camino Community College District and its affiliates. El Camino Community College District may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

El Camino Community College District does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. El Camino Community College District may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, El Camino Community College District may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you e-mail or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to El Camino Community College District, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

El Camino Community College District does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

El Camino Community College District keeps track of the websites and pages our customers visit within El Camino Community College District, in order to determine what El Camino Community College District services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within El Camino Community College District to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

El Camino Community College District websites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on El Camino Community College District or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of El Camino Community College District; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of El Camino Community College District, or the public.

**Use of Cookies**

The El Camino Community College District website use "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize El Camino Community College District pages, or register with El Camino Community College District site or services, a cookie helps El Camino Community College District to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same El Camino Community College District website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the El Camino Community College District features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the El Camino Community College District services or websites you visit.

**Security of your Personal Information**

El Camino Community College District secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. El Camino Community College District secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.  
For the protection of student data (FERPA data) we strictly adhere to the compliance regulations set forth by the Federal Information Security Modernization Act of 2014, also known as the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act, or GLBA.

**Changes to this Statement**

El Camino Community College District will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. El Camino Community College District encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how El Camino Community College District is protecting your information.

**Contact Information**

El Camino Community College District welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that El Camino Community College District has not adhered to this Statement, please contact the El Camino Community College District Office of Marketing & Communications at: [marcomm@elcamino.edu](mailto:marcomm@elcamino.edu). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
